Sudhir Kumar

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Personal Profile

8800583093 skkhatri07@gmail.com

Links

Portfolio

Linkedin

Skills

Java

Spring Boot

Microservices

Spring Batch

Hibernate

Team leadership

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner

Apache Kafka

Team Management

Junit

Power Mockito

Maven

Hobbies

Watching Movies, Programming, Reading Java Blogs

Professional Summary

I'm a Java Developer with 8.6 years of experience in Web Application development using Spring, Hibernate Framework and Restful Webservice in Banking & Finance domains.

- =>Proficiency in development of applications using Core Java, J2EE ,Spring Framework, Hibernate Framework. HTML5, JavaScript.
- =>Worked on database management system like SQL SERVER 2008 / Oracle 10g.
- =>Worked on various phases of SDLC like requirement gathering and analysis, design, coding, testing.
- =>Have excellent analytical, problem solving, communication, and interpersonal skills with ability to interact with individuals at all levels.
- =>Capable of adapting to working on new systems & environments efficiently.

Colleagues know me as a highly creative and efficient Developer who can always be trusted to come up with a new approach. But I know that the client's business comes first, and I never try to impose my ideas on others. Instead, I spend a lot of time understanding the business and the requirements before suggesting ideas. I can (and often do) work well alone, but I'm at my best collaborating with others.

Employment History

Senior Software Engineer, Cognizant, Bengaluru

06/2018

PROJECT TITLE "ANZ - OTC" (Banking & Financial Service Domain)

Project Summary: OTC-RE (Over the counter-Reporting Engine) Over the counter (OTC) refers to the process of how securities are traded for companies that are not listed on a formal exchange such as the New York Stock Exchange (NYSE). Securities that are traded over the counter are traded via a broker-dealer network as opposed to on a centralized exchange.

Roles & Responsibilities:

- To write the Model's, API's, REST's Services. Implementation.
- To implement the user story requirements by understanding it from Business Team.
- To write the Junit Unit Test Code of implemented functionality by using the Mockito Framework.

Software Engineer, HCL Technologies, Noida

05/2016 - 06/2018

PROJECT TITLE: "AT&T" (E-Commerce Domain)

Project Summary: AT&T Inc. is an American multinational

telecommunications corporation, headquartered at Whitacre Tower in downtown Dallas, Texas. AT&T is the second largest provider of mobile telephone and the largest provider of fixed telephone in the United States. After integration with Direct TV the implementation of Add-ons addition is done along with the other existing products of AT&T for all the customers.

Roles & Responsibilities:

• To write the Model's, API's, REST's Services. Implementation.

- To implement the user story requirements on Cart API.
- To integrate the third-party services like Quartz for Job Scheduling.
- To involve in defect prevention activities.
- To write the Test Cases by using Junit, Mockito Framework

Assistant Programmer, National Informatic Centre (On 3rd Party Payroll), Delhi

06/2015 - 04/2016

PROJECT TITLE: "NPP (NATIONAL POWER PORTAL)"

Project Summary: NPDMS is a central government project. NPDMS Envisages to Disseminate Power Sector Information on operational capacity, Demand, Supply, Consumption, New Connections, Consumer Complaints, Rural Electrification, Funding of Schemes etc.

Frameworks: Spring MVC, Spring Boot, Hibernate

Database: PostgreSQL

Roles & Responsibilities:

- To create several reports and multiple generation views like pdf, excel, html, xml, JSON using jasper.
- Distribute tasks to supportive entities who work with it.
- Responding rapidly to escalated issues.

Education

Master of Computer Application, Guru Nanak Dev University, Gurdaspur, Punjab

06/2011 - 07/2014

Bachelor of Computer Application, Binaner University, Sri Ganganagar, Rajasthan

06/2008 - 06/2011

Rajasthan Board, 12th Board, Sri Ganganagar, Rajasthan

01/2008 - 12/2008

Rajasthan Board, 10th Board, Sri Ganganagar, Rajasthan

01/2006 - 12/2006